I have a call to all of the Reggeris Academy in the Moms of the Council.
From Monday, October 3rd, 2022.
We're two proclamation declaring September 17th, 2022 to September 23rd, 2022, as constitution
week in the city of Miami, Oklahoma.
And this was a proclamation with the majority of the American revelations that the lady
called and asked me to do this.
So we put it together.
I think she was scared to speak, but she didn't make it tonight, then look like so.
Three public input.
I'm scared to the personal parents of us.
We have a moon.
Four, dispatch services memorandum of understanding with Ottawa County E911 Trust Authority.
Remember, this is our annual contract we signed with the 911 authority.
They paid the city $5,000 a month.
And then they just started doing a stipend for our dispatchers to kind of boost their
salary.
This is just our annual contract that we've done for our honor, which haven't updated
for this year.
Okay?
You give it there, please.
Absolutely.
How many dispatchers?
I'm sorry.
13, I believe.
We're currently this year, just for your information.
I'm taking over a countywide dispatch.
We have to have dispatch center, county head 1, and we've combined those now and how those
here, currently.
We're getting ready to swap our bill to a hardened facility where we're going to move
everybody to and dispatch for the entire county.
And it just aids in situational awareness and getting people faster and knowing where
everybody's at.
How many different agencies will that be dispensing for?
I currently 23.
So, we do stay very busy and that stipend just helps about what my American provide for our
dispatchers to help.
I do hope that we need at one time what had interest in that.
They did.
They've approached several times to dispatch for Craig County and we have been able to make
that work as far as logistics, more than anything that we're getting as they've seen how well
or work.
Oh, yeah, absolutely.
It's worked very well and you can test this.
You know, you should be, we'd have something going in any call county and see if they're doing
that or we'd transfer somebody.
You know, I give an example, we had a call, a fire call.
It was up by the border and pitcher.
People have reported or from Kansas, so the 911 call went that way, because it didn't necessarily
always get.
closest place to just kind of switch there so they transferred auto-canon the auto-canon transfer to us
By the time we got people rolling in those almost 20 minutes because it got disconnected once and they had to call them back
And then they called back and did the same thing and that is one center and we want to get people
Get people help as fast as we can and that saves lives and property and and for the officers
You know, one dispatcher really with our GSA if you can see where you're at
It just provides extra
For for all public first responders, and then you get a triple if I can't see it turn it on
Does that spill over and down in Delaware County? I'm sorry is that spill over down into Delaware County?
We have I believe a couple fire stations that are Delaware County, but we don't do any
Any other
First one of the other county. They have their own dispatch center and they've also approaches
And we just can't yeah, can't do it all I'll make a motion to a brief
five ratified and authorized chief and police design
Our program contract with the auto-ac County in the amount of 18,000 dollars
This is for our drone program the county we do a lot of deployments for auto-county
We've done a lot of search and rescue stuff for them. I was doing a presentation
My work group was for but
My furnace mixture furnaces over there was asking what we needed that said, you know
We have a great thermal camera. We'd love to have a night vision to go with that to
They do different things and have different special these on it
It's like right it
Santa will do it our perfons and because we do so many missions with them. They were absolutely on board
And I've provided $18,000 for us to join the camera and then a
Small drone from mapping. We've done a lot of 3D mapping for them
They had
several ponds get drained and they had we had to map those
To 3D to show where the water was where it was how many gallons of water were stolen and they've actually got prostitution off those
Just from using our drone work time
So they want to help us to enhance our program because
We fly a lot for them and it's one of the greatest things I've ever seen in my entire life
And you can go out there at night and it lights it up like it's daylight
Because it's got the big spotlight. It's great. It'd be a certified ballata
Yes, to fly commercial you have to be a certified one of seven pilot and myself in detective
crocket. It's our drone team. We're both one of seven pilots and I wouldn't do it the other way.
He wants to know if a city council would qualify.
No, but that is a cool program, right?
It is, we have built a really good program. That's really cool things. And we've saved just a ton of
amount of hours for officers. You know, we go out and search a five acre field, a matter of minutes,
where it would take, you know, 10, 15 officers walking this thing. And several captures, several
rescues and just been amazing tool for it. Or maybe fly through a house? We have done that here. We've got some
inside stuff. We fly through the house. And we've, we've not tried to limit ourselves. We think it's
possible. We'll try it. And third and night that we got ran from a scene or something in the night
vision, caught him up in a tree. Yes, we're walking right under him. Yeah, but we actually let him in. It was a
pursuit. And I don't remember where it started. I'm in Delaware County down somewhere by Bernace. And
we get there. The guy told us car had his wife and three kids in the car. We ran off and left
him in the car. And so they secured the perimeter. We get there, put up. And it took us maybe a minute,
maybe two minutes to find him. He just blows up. So we get him. And it's got a laser, a laser,
a rain finder on it. So we can from the drone, laser him, laser guys. This may feed a head of
you. And we watch him climb up a tree and he's hugging this branch and walked him in and we're here. We're
here. We're here. We're looking up. We're here. They are very impressive tools. So we're fortunate to
do this kind of support from County. Yeah. I like to fight the tools that we can use for everybody.
Yeah, absolutely. And we've, we've flown for every department of city on my own. We do, we try to
use it for absolutely everything we think of. And I'll flown for robber on fires for code enforcement
parks, utilities. It might say, hey, we need this or this work. Should we try to work? And then I'll
flown for Brian for Buffalo Run to be joy there for fourth of July and parking and just different
events. Yeah, we're working with the fire nurse. It's the city city and travel. It is cool.
I would love to. We have, you know, I can broadcast it right here and go fly somewhere and you can watch screen right there and see if anything will do.
This is the same one that we have the head set on and you're flying around and watching it at the 4th of July.
We have that one. We have a couple though, yeah.
You know, I could put it up right now for our feet and get the front doors above my run.
It's coming.
So Brad, it's one of the only counts. You'll be the one running through the woods and climbing a tree.
Well, probably the most agile one here.
I'll make a motion. We approve the arpegrant.
Hi.
Thank you.
I'm six.
Twenty three to zero seven journal funds grant donations dispatched police department.
Nine one one stipend changes.
Police department, county, arpe award.
Since you gave it, H.T. All the money we've got to lie in the spend it now.
That's what this budget amendment does.
So.
We spent 18,000.
I spent 18,000 that you just approved for him to get.
With the $1,000 stipends last year.
They took the taxes out of that to share the tribe.
All right, I mean, not one one one one to pay them a $4,000.
So the taxes come up on top of that.
And that's what this allows us to do is to pay those additional taxes where they net a
$1,000.
Instead of grossed in a $1,000.
That $1,000 per dispatcher.
I don't know how he split it up exactly.
No.
You said a thousand a month.
Yes, not for.
Not for this.
That's total.
Then by that.
It's out of training.
It may be a long journey or a.
It's not a mistake.
Make most of it.
Thank you, Mike.
Seven.
Purchase 107 L. South East for the son of 13,228 dollars.
That's part of the FEMA grant 4438-016 acquisition.
Domolution grant.
According to the hazard mitigation point.
Yeah.
So these are these next seven items are the seven residential houses.
that are left on that, to be in the grant that we're going to demo, or anticipating closing
on each of these on the 6th and 7th of this week.
The bid packet is being reviewed right now, hopefully, by the end of this week, it'll go
out.
How do you get it?
So all of the properties that are in this specific grant this go around were red tagged properties
from the 2019 flood that we had, so the three commercial properties, which we've already
taken down, and then these seven residential properties.
So it depends on where they're at in the process as far as whether they were planning
to rehab the property or whether they were just going to walk away from it.
According to the FEMA guidelines, we have to take either the assessor value or the latest
appraisal on a property.
Well, there's a mixture of them here that, so I'm going to say that primarily the ones that
are located on L, southeast that are lower in value were appraisals, and I think there might be
one or two of them that are a little bit higher in those were assessor.
Number eight, purchased property, 11, L southeast for some $20,000, $78, or the same
FEMA grant.
Yes.
There are no objections, I think most of them we do, so items, seven, three, two, three.
13.
Yes.
How's that going?
Thank you.
14.
It's energy and the staff recommends we approve items 15 and 16.
17.
Letter of engagement with Archive Social for Archiving Social Media Records in the amount of $299.
It's the same when we approve it in the meeting and I'll make a motion to approve.
18.
Mayor's nomination to re-appoint Shannon do harm to the Maori community facilities authority.
Board termed expire 12.
3 of 27.
19.
Mayor's nomination to re-appoint Dr. Jeff Stewart to the airport authority board termed expire 11.20
26.
20.
Maybe any new business, which is written since the posting of this agenda.
21.
Stafford Works.
22.
Mayor and Council committee announcements.
15.
City management communications on the behalf of Bo Reese.
24.
Jeremy.